{
  "reference_number": "10271",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Carbon Dioxide - Reducing net carbon dioxide emissions to zero by 2050",
      "answer_index": 13,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "At present only forestry is considered to be a carbon sink, whereas fast growing plants are not recognised. Such as grass and flax\n\n (riparian plantings)."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "More research on cows etc producing methane is underway and the results of this could have considerable bearing on what needs\n to be done."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Insufficient information to make a decision. At present only forestry is considered to be a carbon sink, whereas fast growing plants are\n not recognised. Such as grass and flax (riparian plantings)."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "We don't know what climate change is going to do."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "It needs to be able to be reviewed regularly as circumstances change. But a plan is needed."
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Work with forestry - because forestry needs to respect waterways as do farmers. Forestry companies need to plant the riparian strip\n\nto prevent (a) waste going into waterways after harvesting, (b) to keep a continuous barrier between pine exudate and waterways to\nensure streamlife remains healthy. (c) to prevent soil erosion. (d) this would also ensure some carbon sinking continues during\n\nharvesting."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Advisory with mechanisms built in to hold a government to account."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Amazing if you can get people with all that expertise! People with a practical point of view are important. Not all theoretical, academic\nand narrow point of views."
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "maybe.... this seems to be happening at present. There needs to be good communication between all groups and the population."
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "At present only forestry is considered to be a carbon sink, whereas fast growing plants are not recognised. Such as grass, cabbage\n\ntrees, manuka and flax (riparian plantings). Riparian planting should be undertaken for all new developments to protect waterways\nand to act as a carbon sink in town and country. When making decisions about different communities and regions there should be\nopportunities for those with local knowledge to have input as in the past decisions have been made by groups of people in\n\nWellington that do not take into account local conditions and things that could easily be solved by good communication with all\nparties. For example: Spending huge amounts of money on the Brynderwyn Hills when the problem had been solved by reducing the\n\nspeed limit to 80 kph. (Information from local Fire Parties who attend accidents in that area). And now they are talking about building a\nwhole new motorway away from the Brynderwyns. A waste of taxpayers money. Very poor planning. Let's not make the same mistake\n\ntwice."
    }
  ]
}
